<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Lord Bruce and the Lady Elizabeth Bruce his wife, desire a bill may be passed in Parliament, relating no manner of way to the cutting off entails, nor the selling of land, nor the least to the prejudice of their children, nor any other reversions, as by the Bill appears.</title>
            <author>Elgin, Thomas Bruce, Earl of, 1655?-1741.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B18231</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99887515</idno>
  <idno type="VID">190493</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240882498</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing B5220D</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide L.R.305.a.7.[29]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R227804</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99887515</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99887515e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B18231)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 190493)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C21:2[94])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Lord Bruce and the Lady Elizabeth Bruce his wife, desire a bill may be passed in Parliament, relating no manner of way to the cutting off entails, nor the selling of land, nor the least to the prejudice of their children, nor any other reversions, as by the Bill appears.</title>
                  <author>Elgin, Thomas Bruce, Earl of, 1655?-1741.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing CD-ROM, 1996.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Debtor and creditor --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Estates (Law) --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Annuities --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:190493:1"/>
            <head>The Lord BRUCE and the Lady ELIZABETH BRUCE his Wife, desire a Bill may be passed in Parliament, Relating no manner of way to the cutting off Entails, nor the selling of Land, nor in the least to the prejudice of their Children, nor any other Reversions, as by the Bill appears.</head>
            <p>SOME persons out of a worthy intent, desired that an Application by way of Reference might be made to my Lady <hi>Elizabeth Bruce's</hi> Mother the Duchess of <hi>Beaufort,</hi> who opposes every individual Article of the Bill, her reasons for it yet unknown.</p>
            <p>An Application was made, and four days spent in it, two or three Meetings each day ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed and put off to their great prejudice.</p>
            <p>The Lord <hi>Bruce</hi> came to this fair Proposition, That he would refer the whole business to any one person she would name, and to stand to his Award whatever it was.</p>
            <p>At the end of four days the Duchess of <hi>Beaufort</hi> was waited upon by the Lord <hi>Bruce</hi> and his Referee, the several particulars of the Bill were Read, a general Objection to them all, with no other answer but <hi>Sic Volo sic Jubeo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Not any one particular of the Bill is of any advantage to the Lord <hi>Bruce,</hi> but only to rectifie some omissions and make some alterations in an agreement made last year, which was consented to most unwillingly by the Lord <hi>Bruce</hi> and his Lady, being compelled thereunto, by reason of the great and uncontroulable power the Duchess of <hi>Beaufort</hi> had over the Estate, occasioned by Settlements many years since at her former Marriage, and by some obtained Settlements at the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Bruce's</hi> Marriage; which were most unwillingly consented to, it being thought very hard to be imposed on to settle half her Estate on her Brother the Earl of <hi>Worcester,</hi> who was but of the half Blood, in case she had no Children, which contingency is the only reason this unreasonable opposition is made, although it be pretended it is done for the good of the Children, the Father and Mother being conceived to be persons who wholly study the ruine of them.</p>
            <p>There is a Debt of 15000 <hi>l.</hi>which remains as yet unpaid, or most part of it, which is acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledged to be a Debt contracted for the payment of the Debts and Annuities the Estate was charged with before the Marriage, this they say must be paid before any part shall be applied to the Lord <hi>Bruce's</hi> use, contrary to a promise which can be made upon Oath, that a certain yearly allowance should be consented to, until the debt was paid, but because it was not under Hand and Seal, it is thought not binding although a firm promise, it being nine years since the Marriage, and during the whole time not one Farthing of that Estate has been applied to any use but paying the Debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of <hi>John</hi> late Duke of <hi>Somerset;</hi> and the Lord <hi>Bruce</hi> has disbursed of his own proper Mony above 4000 <hi>l.</hi> for the same use, which is denied to be paid, and took up after above 20000 <hi>l.</hi> more at one time on his own security, to free the Estate from the Debts and Legacies, and by consequence many Law Suits which were commenced for the same, and every part of it is Confessed to be applied its to use; and yet they refuse to have the said Debt charged on the Estate, as also to allow the Interest thereof: Which unheard of Proceedings, the Lord and Lady <hi>Bruce</hi> Humbly pray to be relieved from.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>